aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth, Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these brave heroes powers.
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해 우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 부여한 용자(勇者)들
Their name is Dagwon.
그 이름은 다그온
Now, a new comrade has joined them.
그들에게 지금 새로운 동료가 가담했다
That planet is our target.
저게 목적의 별이다
What a blue planet!
정말 푸른 별이구나
That's right.
그 말대로다...
It is the perfect environment for me to take root in grounds, spread branches, and keep growing without limit.
내가 뿌리를 내리고 가지를 뻗어, 한없이 커다랗게 성장하기에 딱 알맞은 환경이다
What's the name of that planet?
저 별 이름이 뭐야?
It's Earth.
'지구'란다...
Earth, huh...
지구인가...
A Big Tree from Space
우주의 거대한 나무
Mechanical Plant Mekaju Seijin
Gundroid T96
Appears
기계 식물 메카쥬 성인 건드로이드 T96 등장
Principal, I have a question.
교장 선생님, 질문이 있는데요
What is it?
뭔가?
The site of this school...
이 학교 터 말이에요
what was it a long time ago?
옛날엔 뭐였나요?
A long time ago?
옛날이라니?
A long time before the school was built.
학교가 세워지기 훨씬 전
Maybe up to Edo era?
예를 들면, 에도(江戶)시대 같은 때 말이예요
I guess it was a plain mountain back then.
글쎄... 평범한 산이 아니었을까?
But I can feel a strong spiritual presence from the back mountain of this school.
하지만, 학교 뒷산 근처에서 꽤 강력한 영기가 느껴져요
Could it be the place where people without relatives were buried?
혹시, 옛날에는 무연불(無緣佛)을 매장하는 묘지였다던가...
Or...
아니면...
According to Tobe, it seems that every place becomes a site with spirit!
토베 양에게 걸리면, 어디든지 영이 깃든 것이 되는 것 같군
No way, principal!
너무해요~ 교장 선생님도 참...
Anyway, how's your Supernatural Phenomenon Research Club going?
그건 그렇고, 요즘 초상현상 연구회 쪽은 어떤가?
Did you manage to recruit some staffs?
조금이라도 부원은 늘었는가?
Not at all...
그게... 전혀...
Good morning.
안녕하십니까?
Ryu?
류?
Hashiba, you came.
여어, 하시바. 이제 오는겐가
You can have some vegetables again.
또 야채 받아가게나
Thank you for all time.
매번 죄송합니다
To see the vivid color of this eggplant, I always want to say thanks to the mother earth.
나는 말이지, 가지의 이 산뜻한 빛깔을 보고 있으면 언제나 대지에게 감사하고 싶어진다네
The Earth is truly a wonderful planet.
지구는 정말 훌륭한 별이지
I agree.
동감입니다
Got it!
왔다!
Hey, Yoku!
여봐, 요쿠
Whatcha doin'?
뭐 하고 있어?
Hey, Shin!
아아, 신
I'm disposing of the data about Dagwon and the aliens that we don't need anymore.
우주인과 다그온에 관한 자료 중에서 필요없어진 것들을 처분하고 있습니다
In a way people wouldn't notice.
다른 사람 눈에 띄지 않게 말이죠
That's great!
오호~ 그거 마침 잘 됐구만
Look at this.
이거 좀 봐라
For some reason, my family received only beef as a present for Bon festival gifts.
우리집, 백중날 선물로 어째선지 쇠고기만 잔뜩 들어와서 말야
My lunch box is full of raw meat.
오늘 내 도시락, 전부 날고기라니깐
My mother told me to roast it myself in the school!
엄마도 참, 학교에서 적당히 구워 먹으란다
In that case, you can use this fire.
과연, 그럼 이 불로 구워 먹으면 되겠군요
Lucky! So, let's do it!
럭키~ 그럼 지금 당장...
Whare you guys doing?
뭐하고 있어, 너희들?
-Hey, Kai!
-Did you go fishing?
-아, 카이
-뭐야, 낚시 갔다 오냐?
This is perfect! We now have vegetables!
이거 마침 잘 됐다 야채까지 왔구만!
Isn't this place the room for Supernatural Phenomenon Research Club?
여기는 초상현상 연구회의 부실 아니냐?
Yeah, that's right.
아, 맞아
Nicknamed Occult Research Club.
별명하여 오컬트 연구회
Say, I don't see any other members else than Maria.
그러고보니, 마리아 씨 말고는 부원이 전혀 보이질 않는군
Geki, didn't you know?
게키, 너 아직 몰랐냐?
The only member of the Occult Research Club is Maria. That's all.
오컬트 연구회의 부원은 말이지 마리아 달랑 혼자라구
Only Maria?
마리아 씨 혼자라고?
Yep. Why would anyone want to enter this stupid club?
그래, 이런 괴상한 클럽에 들어올 녀석이 있을 리 없잖아
What's wrong?
왜그래?
Hey, um... I just wonder... I just wonder...
저기, 만약... 만약에 말인데 말야...
If I say I want to enter this group,
내가 입부 희망한다고 하면...
will Maria let me do so?
마리아 씨, 받아주실까?
Hey, I didn't know you were interested in occult things!
너, 오컬트 같은 거에 흥미 있었냐?
Nah, that's not it...
아니;;; 그런 건 아니지만...
Then is there anything good about entering this club?
그럼 이런 클럽에 들어와서 뭐 득 볼 거라도 있냐?
No, that is... in other words...
아니;;; 그... 그러니까...
Huh? I smell something good.
어레, 왠지 좋은 냄새가 나는데?
Huh? I smell something roasted.
음? 확실히 창 밖에서 구수한 냄새가...
-It's going well.
-Right, right!
-잘 익는구만
-맞아요 맞아요
Hey, everyone!
어레, 너희들?
Smells good!
냄새 좋구만
Hey, En and Geki!
오오, 엔과 게키
I guess you were in my research room without my permission?
아아, 너희들 또 내 부실에 맘대로 들어갔지?
Don't be so selfish!
쫀쫀하게 그러지 말라니까
By the way, you should have let me know about this!
그것보다, 모두들 이런데 모여서 요리냐?
Do you want to eat too?
너희들도 먹을래?
It will be ready soon.
이제 곧 익습니다
It sure looks tasty.
오호, 고녀석 참 맛있게 생겼군
Oh, right. Some soy sauce will help too.
아, 맞다 간장이 있는게 좋겠구나
Right. We cannot omit soy sauce.
역시 간장은 빠질 수 없지
Then I'll take it from the cooking practice room!
그럼, 가정 실습실에서 가져올게
Anyway, how lucky to have a barbecue party in morning!
그건 그렇고, 아침부터 바베큐라니 이거 횡재구만
Let's hurry and eat!
얼른 먹자구
It looks so good!
잘 익었구만
Thank you!
잘 먹겠습니다!
That's...
저건...!
I-it can't be! An alien from Sargasso?
서, 설마 사르갓소의 우주인?
Let's go follow it!
추적하자!
Alright! Let's go!
좋아! 출동이다!
Right!
오우!
Where did everybody go?
모두들 어디 갔지?
Okay, somewhere around this place will be perfect.
좋아... 이 근처로 정하자
-Prepare to fire the Vulcan cannon!
-OK!
-발칸포 발사 준비!
Start the attack!
공격 개시!
It is an alien from Sargasso!
사르갓소의 우주인이구만!
What is this?
뭐하는 녀석들이지?!
He's so quick!
미꾸라지 같은 녀석!
What a slippery bastard!
정말 재빠른 녀석입니다!
It's hard to aim at that guy!
이녀석, 재빨라서 맞추기가 힘들어!
Did we lose him?
놓쳐버렸나...
Let's attack before they interfere with us.
이번엔 방해꾼이 나타나기 전에 공격하자
Got it!
알았어!
That looks like the perfect ground.
지면이 딱 알맞게 되었군
Let's take root in that place right now!
지금 바로 저기에 뿌리를 내리도록 하자
-Understood?
-OK!
-알겠지?
That's...
저건?!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우
The tree is withering!
나무가... 시들어가고 있어!
This is-!
이건...?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
I will be never able to understand those guys.
정말... 이해가 안되는 녀석들이라니까
When I came back, everybody left!
돌아와 봤더니, 아무도 없더라구요
Those guys are really weird.
정~말 이상한 녀석들이예요
I guess they found that they forgot something important?
뭔가 중요한 일이라도 생각난 거겠지
They surprised me!
사람 놀래키고 말야
It will be alright.
신경쓰지 말게
My vegetables are perfect for the cosmetics, Tobe.
내가 기른 야채는 미용에 최적이라네, 토베 양
-Alright!
-Let's go!
-좋아!
-간다!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)
Dag Drill!
다그 드릴
What the heck is this tree?
뭐냐, 이 나무는?
We can't let our guard down.
방심할 수 없는 상대다
No need to worry.
신경쓸 거 없어
It's nothing more than a tree after all!
어차피 그냥 나무잖아?
If the enemy cannot move, there's nothing to worry about!
움직이지도 못하는 적이라면 두려울 거 없지
Alright! Let's attack at once!
좋아! 어쨌든 일제히 공격하자
Yeah!
오우!
Fire Knuckle!
파이어 너클!
Drill Pulsar!
드릴 펄서!
Shadow Shot!
섀도우 슛!
Seems that it has a barrier!
아차... 바리어인가?
This guy is more cumbersome than I thought!
이녀석, 생각보다 성가신 녀석이구만
Alright! Fire Jumbo! Launch!
좋아, 파이어 점보!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
Jet Fire Missile!
제트 파이어 미사일!
What the hell is this big tree bastard?
이 거대한 나무 같은 녀석은 대체 뭐지?!
It was a plant-shaped alien who was riding a flying mecha moments ago.
좀전의 비행 메카에 타고 있던 식물형 우주인이야
Did it become this big?
이렇게나 커졌단 말인가요?
It seems so. It grew so fast.
그래, 눈 깜빡할 새에 성장했어
Anyway, we won't let it get any bigger!
어쨌든, 이대로 놔 둘 수는 없지!
Shadow Shuriken!
섀도우 수리검!
Fire Star Burn!
파이어 스타 번!
We did it!
오옷, 성공이다!
How's that?
어떠냐?!
A mechanical plant lifeform...
기계 식물 생명체인가...
I've never seen something like this.
이런 건 처음 보는군요
What happened to the flying mecha that he used?
저녀석이 타고 온 비행 메카는 어떻게 됐지?
I think it was forced to land in the forest.
숲 속에 불시착한 것 같아
Alright, let's go find it.
좋아, 흩어져서 찾아보자
The comrade of that alien might be still hiding.
아직 저 우주인의 동료가 타고 있을지도 모르니까 말야
Is this it?
이녀석인가?
I think nobody is inside at the moment.
더이상 아무도 타고 있지 않은 것 같군요
Was that alien just before all?
아까 그 녀석 한마리 뿐이었단 건가
What should we do with this plane?
어떻게 하지, 이 비행기?
Since it's the plane of an alien from Sargasso, we have no choice than to destroy it.
사르갓소의 우주인의 비행기니까... 파괴할 수 밖에 없겠군
Alright, leave that to me.
좋아, 그거라면 내가 하지
Final Buster!
파이널 버스터!
Stop it!
그만둬!
Who's there?
누구지?!
Don't shoot!
쏘지 마!
Bye-bye!
바이 바이~
Was that mecha alive?
저 메카, 살아있었단 말인가?!
Please leave pursuit to me!
추적은 제게 맡기세요
I see you!
저기 있군
What are you doing to me?!
우와앗! 무슨 짓이야?!
-Let me go! Let me go!
-Just keep calm!
-싫어~ 싫다니까~!
-좀 얌전히 굴어라!
Let go of me!
이거 놔! 놓으라구!
That bastard is getting annoying!
거 엄청 번거롭게 하는구만, 이녀석!
Prepare yourself!
자아, 각오 하라구!
Run away!
도망쳐라~!
Wh-what did that guy-?
뭐, 뭐냐 저녀석?!
Is it a robot?
로봇이었단 말인가?
Hey! Stop right there!
여봐! 기다려!
Damn, that punk!
제길! 저녀석!
Help me! Help me!
살려줘~ 살려줘~
There's no use in running away! Behave yourself!
도망쳐도 소용 없다! 자, 얌전히 굴어라
I'll shoot you!
쏘, 쏠거다!
Wh-what?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
If you bully me, I'll shoot you!
괴롭히면 진짜로 쏠 거야!
W-wait a sec!
자, 잠깐 기달려봐;;;
It's dangerous to aim that big gun at me!
그렇게 커다란 총을 사람한테 겨누면 위험하잖아
Feh! We'll have to destroy it with our all out attack!
칫! 이렇게 되면 전원 총공격으로 저녀석을 파괴해 버리자!
As long as we have to!
그 수 밖에 없나...
Just a moment!
잠깐 기다려!
Look over there!
저길 봐!
What's going on? Was there another one?
어떻게 된 거야?! 한마리 더 있었단 말인가!
No.
아닙니다
That is a mechanical lifeform with the form of a plant.
이녀석은 식물의 성질을 가진 기계 생명체입니다
I guess its root remaining in the ground sprouted.
아마 지하에 이어져 있던 뿌리가 싹을 틔운 거겠죠
We gotta do whatever it takes!
이렇게 되면 이판사판이다!
Anyway let's take this guy down!
어쨌든 이녀석도 끝장내 버리자!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Final Buster!
파이널 버스터!
Crystal Cutter!
크리스탈 커터!
Shadow Vulcan!
섀도우 발칸!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
Damn! Nothing's working!
젠장! 전혀 먹히질 않는구만!
What the?!
아니?!
Infinity...
무한..
무한...
Infinity...
무한....
Yes, sir!
예이~
What?!
아니?!
Feel the might of the Infinity Cannon!
무한포(無限砲)의 위력을 뼈저리게 느껴봐라!
Stop!
그만둬!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
That Infinity Cannon has a frighteningly destructive power. It will be a difficult battle.
엄청난 파괴력을 가진 무한포. 힘든 상대야
What are you talking about? With my Drill Liner, it's nothing.
무슨 약한 소리?! 나의 드릴 라이너가 있다면, 별거 아니라구
But anyway, we happened to take that Infinite Cannon by force. We should also take this guy down.
하지만 말야, 여차해서 무한포는 빼앗았는데, 이녀석 역시 부술 수 밖에 없겠지?
That's too harsh!
아앗, 그건 너무 불쌍하잖아!
Let's do as Gaku says.
가쿠 군 말대로 하자
Why would you listen to Gaku?
왜 가쿠 말 따위를 듣는 거냐?
That is... he's a brother of Maria!
그건... 마리아 씨 동생이잖나...
I can't stand you like that!
못 봐 주겠구만
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! The Name is Gunkid
다음회 용자지령 다그온
그 이름은 건키드
It means that another new comrade is going to join us!
또 새로운 동료의 등장이라는 거다!
The Name is Gunkid
그 이름은 건키드